Hello.
In this next lecture, I'm going to go over the other method that we can use to create a 2D background,
and that is to use a tar map.
A tar map will allow us to stack these images on top of one another and create a cool looking background
to create a tar map, Right click and go paper to DH, then select tar map.
Cool this AR background to map.
In order to make our images work the tarmac, we need to convert them into tile sets.
But that is very easy to do.
If we just set all these three images right click and go separate actions.
Then select create to offset.
This will make a tile set for each of the images.
Next, if we open up our background tile map and underactive tile set, just select background one.
I'm now going to go over how to use this tool.
So currently we have this grid.
If I go over to my background, one to set and select any square.
Then if I go back to my grid, I can paint with my left mouse button anywhere on the square and or paint
the color that I've selected.
So maybe I'll select here and then I can paint this part of the cube, this color.
If, say, I wanted to remove a square, I can go to erase and then select anywhere in my tar map.
If I wanted to fill my time up with one color, I can select anywhere here, then go to the fill tool
and select and I'll fill my whole grid.
If we want to adjust the size of this, we can go to map width and map out the Now make the map width
ten.
And the map might six because those are the exact dimensions of this image.
Then if we just select this whole image and go to paint and just paint this image in this box, once
you've done this just right, click on this layer and rename it back.
Now, the reason we're naming this back is because this is going to be our back layer.
And if we just go here, we can add another layer on top of this layer.
Right click on this layer and rename it our middle.
Then if we go to active offset, change this to be background two and select all of this image and then
paste it on here with middle selected.
So now we have placed this tar map on top of our back tar map.
We're going to add one more layer.
So we go add new layer and just rename this front.
Then if we go to active toolset and select the background three to offset, just select everything and
then paste it here.
And now we've added this background on top of our other two layers.
If you want to move around the order of the layers, just select one.
So if I take this front layer and then click this button, it will send this layer towards the back.
If I want to move it forward, I can click this bring forward arrow and this will move it forward.
Okay, nice.
With this, we have created a tower map which has multiple layers.
If we just close this.
And we can't delete this sprite.
And instead drag in our background and scale it up.
So make it 70.
And just position this behind our player character.
I'm actually going to scale this to 140 as it's not big enough.
I'm going to create two copies of this.
And just place the second one here.
And now I go play.
I have this cool 2D background with multiple layers.